Justin Le Tourneau

Address Phone Email Website

Columbia, MO 65201 (636) 697-2120 justin.letourn@gmail.com justin-letourneau.dev

Motivated Programmer and System Administrator with 8 years of experience designing, writing and deploying software for a variety of systems and use cases. Committed to improving user experiences through interface usability and functionality. Seeking a position that values learning, critical thinking and autonomy.

Skills

Programming:

- Proficient in various modern languages:
 - o Ruby, Python, Javascript (ECMAScript), C++, Java, Perl, PHP, Shell Scripting
- Completed web projects using modern frameworks with loaders, bundlers and builders:
 - Web Front-End Vue.js, React.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass, Webpack build tools, etc.
 - Web Back-End Node.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, ColdFusion, Groovy, Django
 - $\circ \quad \text{Web Services} \quad \text{- Socket.io, REST, SOAP, GraphQL, Sequelize, web tokens, etc.}$
- Completed mobile projects using Java, currently experimenting with Flutter
 Completed desktop projects using C++ in Microsoft WinForms and Qt
- Worked with search engines like Lucene and Elasticsearch
- Use, setup, optimize and designed schemas within different database implementations
 - SQL Postgresql, SQLite
 - NoSQL MongoDB, ArangoDB, Neo4j
- Interface design and mockup with Mockflow and Adobe XD
- Git for version control and project organization

Administration:

- Install and manage CentOS, Redhat and Debian servers and virtual machines
- Manage web servers (Nginx, Apache, Tomcat, R Shiny, etc.)
- Add and upgrade hardware, install and compile software and manage storage
- Monitor performance. Manage system resources.
- Relational (and non relational) database administration and optimization (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.)
- Scripting automated backups and other repetitive tasks
- Working with stakeholders to address needs for storage, setup, and provisioning. Implement standards for data storage and archiving.
- Teach researchers the terminal, the linux environment and how to use software like SLURM, Perl, Bash, etc.

Work History

Research Analyst - Linux Administrator, 2016 to Current University Of Missouri – Columbia, Missouri

- Created a data portal, educational and other research websites for National Science Foundation grant project
- Managed, archived and maintained all research data for Missouri EPSCoR state wide grant project
- Write and maintain bioinformatics research software for genome assembly browsers and genomic data mining
- Collaborate with faculty, postdocs and students to solve technical problems and contribute to research projects.
 - Help with R stats, writing and running SLURM jobs, writing scripting / programming for pipelines and projects (C++, Shell, Javascript, Python, Ruby, etc.)
- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Contributed software for research papers on genetic tools, bioinformatics and educational software} \\$
- Maintain 10 high-performance research servers and many (20 or so) kvm / vmware virtual machines
- Installed and managed software (WARF, R, Matlab, genetic pipelines, SMRTLink, etc.) for statewide project (EPSCoR) servers and research lab servers
- Installed, configured and maintained backups and machine images

Quetza Software CTO, 2018 to Current Quetza Software LLC – Columbia, Missouri

- Founded software company for developing agricultural educational products for academic and industry use
- Single full-stack developer for SeeGenetics and SeeBeefGenetics web applications. Created applications, authentication service, key / licensing software, educator portal and AI game companion. Designed both game and key features.
- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Collaborated with co-founder (PhD in Genetics) to hone educational content} \\$

Programmer Analyst, 2012 to 2016 **University Of Missouri** – Columbia, Missouri

- Built custom web applications for financial officers and controllers
- Wrote software to interface with credit card companies and the campus bookstore
- Re-wrote old, custom, legacy software and re-tooled for modern use and maintenance
- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Created custom framework for quickly building financial reports }$

Freelance Developer, 2006 to 2012 **Self Employed** – St. Louis, Missouri

- Wrote software and web applications for various clients in the St. Louis area, for example:
 - C. Rallo Meat Company
 - created software to link scales together for pricing information
 - created mobile apps for various in-store calculations and pricing
 - $\circ \hspace{0.5cm} \textbf{Saint Louis Wrestling Officials Association Scheduling website for Missouri high schools and officials} \\$

Education

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics And Computer Science, 2011 **Webster University** - Webster Groves, MO